Rachelle Adams

770.881.2242 • adamsrachelle@icloud.com • linkedin.com/in/adamsrachelle

PROFILE

Diligent and articulate office administrator with the demonstrated capacity to learn skills quickly and apply them effectively. Possesses a keen aptitude for efficiency, organization, and technology. An instinctive leader with more than 10 years of experience assisting stakeholders at all levels.

EXPERIENCE

Permit Specialist, Community Development

City of Smyrna; Smyrna, GA • March 2022–Present

- Intakes construction plans and distributes documents to appropriate City departments for review
- Performs preliminary plan reviews to verify documents comply with minimum submittal requirements
- Monitors permitting timeline and communicates with public on behalf of department reviewers
- Manages calendars, correspondence, documents, and reports for Chief Building Official

Office Assistant, Community Development

City of Smyrna; Smyrna, GA • August 2020–March 2022

- Facilitated department functions related to permitting, planning & zoning, and business licensing
- Maintained knowledge of City ordinances to accurately inform citizens
- Scheduled daily inspections for Chief Building Official and site inspectors
- Prepared department status reports for City administration and constituents

Scheduling Coordinator

Atlanta Arbor Tree Care Specialist; Marietta, GA • August 2016–August 2020

- Managed production calendar to meet and exceed daily revenue goals
- Organized full cycle of scheduling, including permitting, route planning, and equipment allocation
- Coordinated planning and budgeting for quarterly company events
- Provided administrative support to company management and served as front desk reception

Sales Manager

Lane Bryant; Kennesaw, GA • August 2014–July 2016

- Built and retained clientele through consultative sales and product expertise
- Trained staff in customer service and operational best practices to drive positive KPI results
- Analyzed store performance data to identify sales opportunities and develop team strengths
- Managed back-office administration to comply with monthly audits

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Business Administration in Economics, Minor in Film Studies • 2012

Kennesaw State University, Michael J. Coles College of Business; Kennesaw, GA

SKILLS

Office Management, Project Management, Data Entry, Data Analysis, Research, Customer Service, Team Leadership, Employee Training & Development, Content Creation, Social Media, Windows, macOS, Microsoft Office, Apple iWork, Google G Suite, QuickBooks